Resume

Arun P Menon

Phone: +919544555755

Mailto: arunmenon2006@gmail.com

Website: www.arunmenon.co.nr





Objective

To Acquire A Challenging Position In An Environment Where I Can Best Utilize My Skills And Education.

Roles and Responsibilities

Current Role: Development Lead

Role Responsibilities

Developing custom solutions in Salesforce and provide support for Salesforce projects. Mentor team members. Provide daily status update to client. Assign cases logged in case management tool by client to team members and provide assistance if required. Monitoring the progress of user stories.

Technical Skills

Skills	Salesforc Administration, Salesforce development using Apex,		
	Visualforce, Salesforce integration using middlewares and web		
	services, ASP.Net, SQL Server, WCF, Ektron, C#, CSS		
Tools	TFS, Tortoise SVN, Pivotal Tracker		
Methods	Agile, Waterfall		
Domain Experience	Publishing, Healthcare, Banking, Utilities, Retail		

Achievements

Salesforce Certified Developer, Salesforce Certified Administrator, Microsoft Certified Professional Developer

Additional Details

Worked on developing Salesforce app exchange app and successfully published in appexchange.

Experience Summary

Customer	Leading Retail client in UK	
Role	Development Lead	
Period	01/07/2015 to Till Now	
Technical Skills	Apex, Visualforce, JQuery, Service Cloud	
Achivement	Successfully implemented a major service	
	cloud customization for the client and got good	
	feedback from client.	
Description	Client was not fully utilizing Salesforce and we	

Resume

Resume

rtocarrio	
	designed their Service Cloud as per their
	business needs so that they can respond to
	customer request in a better way.

Customer	Leading Utilities client in UK
Role	Support Lead
Period	15/12/2014 to 31/06/2015 - 6 Months
Technical Skills	Apex, Visualforce, Apex Dataloader, Talend
	Data Integration Tool
Achivement	I was able to fix an issue related to a trigger
	developed previously. The trigger was handling
	1 records at a time. So I re-write that code to
	handle bulk records at time.
Description	Support custom application developed using
	Visualforce and Apex. Manage daily data
	backup and data load using apex dataloader.
	As a Support lead, I need to provide daily
	status update to client in UK. Also need to
	mentor team members. The application is
	developed for a utilities client in UK. The
	purpose of this application is to manage the
	power consumption during peak season. The
	application contains 3 modules:- Registration,
	Dispatch and Settlement.

Customer	Leading Bank in Australia
Role	Lead Developer
Period	09/06/2014 to 05/12/2014 - 5.97 Months
Technical Skills	Salesforce, Apex, Visualforce, Dataloader
	Command Line Interface, Jquery, Windows
	Batch Programming
Achivement	Worked on dataloader automation using
	windows batch and Cygwin utility. Provided
	solution for performance tuning in loading large
	amount of records in visualforce
Description	Worked on implementing custom functionality
	in salesforce to migrate data from 3rd party
	system to salesforce. Interacting with client to
	understand their requirements. Presenting
	demo of the application to client.

Organisation	Ind-Sigma Infotech Pvt Ltd Renamed As Suyati
	Techn
Customer	The College of Social Work
Role	Team Lead
Period	30/12/2013 to 30/04/2014 - 4.03 Months
Technical Skills	Salesforce, SQL Server, SQL Job, DBAmp,
	Apex, Visualforce
Achivement	
Description	Project involved migration of data from SQL
	Server database to Salesforce using ETL Tool
	and creating a custom analytic report using
	visualforce and apex. Another task involved
	reviewing existing code base of the client and
	modifying code to increase its code coverage.

Organisation	Ind-Sigma Infotech Pvt Ltd Renamed As Suyati	
	Techn	
Customer	Author Solutions	
Role	Senior Developer	
Period	23/08/2011 to 27/12/2013 - 28.57 Months	
Technical Skills	ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, Ektron, Salesforce,	
	Apex, Visualforce, Force.com sites	
Achivement	Developed a Salesforce app and published in	
	appexchange	
Description	Worked for a publishing firm in US.	
	Responsibilities include code review,	
	development in .net, implementing new	
	features in Salesforce and maintenance of	
	salesforce instance.	

Organisation	Solistech Solutions	
Customer	Solistech Solutions	
Role	Senior Developer	
Period	01/12/2010 to 19/08/2011 - 8.7 Months	
Technical Skills	ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, Javascript, JQue	
	Salesforce, Apex, Visualforce	
Achivement		
Description	Worked on developing web applications and	
	integration of websites with salesforce for the	
	clients of Solistech	

_	
Organisation	Aadhocc Software Technologies

Resume

Customer	Aadhocc Software Technologies	
Role	Developer	
Period	01/02/2010 to 26/11/2010 - 9.93 Months	
Technical Skills	ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, Javascript	
Achivement		
Description Worked on developing web application		
	ASP.Net, C# and SQL Server. Worked on full	
	SDLC including requirement gathering to	
	testing.	

Experience Details

Total Experience	5 YEAR(S),10 MONTH(S)
------------------	-----------------------

Passport Details

Passport Number	Date of Issue	Expiry Date	Place of Issue
H4807810	10-aug-2009	09-aug-2019	Cochin, INDI

Certifications

Title	Acquired On
Salesforce.com Certified Force.com Developer Certification	16/02/2013
Salesforce.com Certified Administrator Certification	18/03/2015

Education Summary

Qualification	Subject	Percentage/Grade
Bachelor Of Technology	Information Technology	60.5
Standard Xii / H.S.C.	Computer Science	75
Ssc	Others	79